A world beyond your experience, beyond your imagination.
Dune is a action, science fiction, adventure film directed by David Lynch.
In the year 10,191, the most precious substance in
the universe is the spice Melange.
The spice extends life.
The spice expands consciousness.
The spice is vital to space travel.
The spice exists on only one planet in the entire universe, the
vast desert planet Arrakis, also known as Dune.
Its native inhabitants, the Fremen, have long held a prophecy that a man
would come, a messiah who would lead them to true freedom.
Paul Atreides, played by Kyle MacLachlan.
Lady Jessica, played by Francesca Annis.
Gurney Halleck, played by Patrick Stewart.
Shadout Mapes, played by Linda Hunt.
Padisha Emperor Shaddam IV, played by José Ferrer.
Thufir Hawat, played by Freddie Jones.
Dune is a 1984 American epic space opera film written and directed by David
Lynch, and based on the 1965 novel of the same name by Frank Herbert.
It was filmed at the Churubusco Studios in Mexico City.
The soundtrack was composed by the rock band Toto,
with a contribution from Brian Eno.
Its large ensemble cast includes Kyle MacLachlan (in his film debut), Patrick Stewart, Brad Dourif, Dean Stockwell,
Virginia Madsen, José Ferrer, Sean Young, Silvana Mangano, Sting, Linda Hunt, and Max von Sydow.
The setting is the distant future, chronicling the conflict between rival noble families as they
battle for control of the extremely harsh desert planet Arrakis, also known as Dune.
The planet is the only source of the drug melange (spice), which allows prescience and is vital to
space travel, making it the most essential and valuable commodity in the universe.
Paul Atreides is the scion and heir of a powerful noble family, whose appointment to the control
of Arrakis brings them into conflict with its former overlords, House Harkonnen.
Paul is also possibly the Kwisatz Haderach, a messianic
figure expected by the Bene Gesserit sisterhood.
After the novel's initial success, attempts to
adapt Dune as a film began in 1971.
A lengthy process of development followed throughout
the 1970s, during which Arthur P.
Jacobs, Alejandro Jodorowsky, and Ridley Scott unsuccessfully
tried to bring their visions to the screen.
In 1981, executive producer Dino De Laurentiis hired Lynch as director.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing $30.9
million against a $40–42 million budget.
At least four versions have been released worldwide.
Lynch largely disowned the finished film and had his name removed or
changed to pseudonyms in the credits on certain versions.
Despite receiving mainly negative reviews upon release, the film has developed a cult
following, but opinion varies between fans of the novel and fans of Lynch's films.
The film explores themes of witch, empire, galaxy, rebellion, future.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.